<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Migraine Trigger</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="nav_home">Home</string>
    <string name="nav_severity">Severity</string>
    <string name="nav_answers">Answers</string>
    <string name="nav_f_a_q">F.A.Q.</string>
    <string name="nav_records">Records</string>
    <string name="nav_report">Report</string>
    <string name="nav_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="nav_about">About</string>
    <string name="dev_email">mithwick93@gmail.com</string>

    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>

    <string name="home_welcome">Welcome</string>

    <string name="app_icon">app icon</string>
    <string name="dev_name">M.S. Wickramarathne</string>
    <string name="app_version">0.1 alpha</string>

    <string name="title_activity_activity_faq">F.A.Q.</string>

    <string name="migraine_definition_para1">"\t\t\tA migraine headache can cause intense throbbing or a pulsing sensation in one area of the head and is commonly accompanied by nausea, vomiting, and extreme sensitivity to light and sound."</string>
    <string name="migraine_definition_para2">"\t\t\tMigraine attacks can cause significant pain for hours to days and be so severe that all you can think about is finding a dark, quiet place to lie down."</string>
    <string name="migraine_definition_para3">"\t\t\tSome migraines are preceded or accompanied by sensory warning symptoms (aura), such as flashes of light, blind spots, or tingling in your arm or leg."</string>
    <string name="migraine_definition_para4">"\t\t\tMedications can help reduce the frequency and severity of migraines. If treatment hasn\'t worked for you in the past, talk to your doctor about trying a different migraine headache medication. The right medicines, combined with self-help remedies and lifestyle changes, may make a big difference."</string>


    <string name="symptoms_para_1">"Migraine headaches often begin in childhood, adolescence or early adulthood. Migraines may progress through four stages, including prodrome, aura, headache and postdrome, though you may not experience all the stages."</string>


    <string name="symptom_section_1_heading">Prodrome</string>
    <string name="symptom_section_1_body">"One or two days before a migraine, you may notice subtle changes that signify an oncoming migraine, including:
	1.Constipation
	2.Depression
	3.Food cravings
	4.Hyperactivity
	5.Irritability
	6.Neck stiffness
	7.Uncontrollable yawning"</string>

    <string name="symptom_section_2_heading">Aura</string>
    <string name="symptom_section_2_body">"Aura may occur before or during migraine headaches. Auras are nervous system symptoms that are usually visual disturbances, such as flashes of light. Sometimes auras can also be touching sensations (sensory), movement (motor) or speech (verbal) disturbances. Most people experience migraine headaches without aura. Each of these symptoms usually begins gradually, builds up over several minutes, and then commonly lasts for 20 to 60 minutes. Examples of aura include:

	* Visual phenomena, such as seeing various shapes, bright spots or flashes of light
	* Vision loss
	* Pins and needles sensations in an arm or leg
	* Speech or language problems (aphasia)
	* Less commonly, an aura may be associated with limb weakness (hemiplegic migraine)."</string>

    <string name="symptom_section_3_heading">Attack</string>
    <string name="symptom_section_3_body">"When untreated, a migraine usually lasts from four to 72 hours, but the frequency with which headaches occur varies from person to person. You may have migraines several times a month or much less often. During a migraine, you may experience the following symptoms:

	* Pain on one side or both sides of your head
	* Pain that has a pulsating, throbbing quality
	* Sensitivity to light, sounds and sometimes smells
	* Nausea and vomiting
	* Blurred vision
	* Lightheadedness, sometimes followed by fainting"</string>

    <string name="symptom_section_4_heading">Postdrome</string>
    <string name="symptom_section_4_body">"The final phase, known as postdrome, occurs after a migraine attack. During this time you may feel drained and washed out, though some people report feeling mildly euphoric."</string>

    <string name="symptom_para_2_heading">See your doctor immediately or go to the emergency room</string>
    <string name="symptom_para_2_body">"If you have any of the following signs and symptoms, which may indicate other, more serious medical problems:

	* An abrupt, severe headache like a thunderclap
	* Headache with fever, stiff neck, mental confusion, seizures, double vision, weakness, numbness or trouble speaking
	* Headache after a head injury, especially if the headache gets worse
	* A chronic headache that is worse after coughing, exertion, straining or a sudden movement
	* New headache pain if you're older than 50"</string>


    <string name="causes_para_1">"Although much about the cause of migraines isn't understood, genetics and environmental factors appear to play a role.

Migraines may be caused by changes in the brainstem and its interactions with the trigeminal nerve, a major pain pathway.

Imbalances in brain chemicals — including serotonin, which helps regulate pain in your nervous system — also may be involved. Researchers continue to study the role of serotonin in migraines.

Serotonin levels drop during migraine attacks. This may cause your trigeminal system to release substances called neuropeptides, which travel to your brain's outer covering (meninges). The result is headache pain."</string>


    <string name="causes_section_1_heading">Hormonal changes in women</string>
    <string name="causes_section_1_body">"Fluctuations in estrogen seem to trigger headaches in many women with known migraines. Women with a history of migraines often report headaches immediately before or during their periods, when they have a major drop in estrogen.

Others have an increased tendency to develop migraines during pregnancy or menopause.

Hormonal medications, such as oral contraceptives and hormone replacement therapy, also may worsen migraines. Some women, however, may find their migraines occur less often when taking these medications."</string>


    <string name="causes_section_2_heading">Foods</string>
    <string name="causes_section_2_body">"Aged cheeses, salty foods and processed foods may trigger migraines. Skipping meals or fasting also can trigger attacks."</string>

    <string name="causes_section_3_heading">Food additives</string>
    <string name="causes_section_3_body">" The sweetener aspartame and the preservative monosodium glutamate, found in many foods, may trigger migraines."</string>

    <string name="causes_section_4_heading">Drinks</string>
    <string name="causes_section_4_body">"Alcohol, especially wine, and highly caffeinated beverages may trigger migraines."</string>

    <string name="causes_section_5_heading">Stress</string>
    <string name="causes_section_5_body">"Stress at work or home can cause migraines."</string>

    <string name="causes_section_6_heading">Sensory stimuli</string>
    <string name="causes_section_6_body">"Bright lights and sun glare can induce migraines, as can loud sounds. Unusual smells — including perfume, paint thinner, secondhand smoke and others — can trigger migraines in some people."</string>

    <string name="causes_section_7_heading">Changes in wake-sleep pattern</string>
    <string name="causes_section_7_body">"Missing sleep or getting too much sleep may trigger migraines in some people, as can jet lag."</string>

    <string name="causes_section_8_heading">Physical factors</string>
    <string name="causes_section_8_body">"Intense physical exertion, including sexual activity, may provoke migraines."</string>

    <string name="causes_section_9_heading">Changes in the environment</string>
    <string name="causes_section_9_body">"A change of weather or barometric pressure can prompt a migraine."</string>

    <string name="causes_section_10_heading">Medications</string>
    <string name="causes_section_10_body">"Oral contraceptives and vasodilators, such as nitroglycerin, can aggravate migraines."</string>


    <string name="risk_section_1_heading">Family history</string>
    <string name="risk_section_1_body">"Up to 90 percent of people with migraines have a family history of migraine attacks. If one or both of your parents have migraines, then you have a good chance of having migraines too."</string>

    <string name="risk_section_2_heading">Age</string>
    <string name="risk_section_2_body">"Migraines can begin at any age, though most people experience their first migraine during adolescence. By age 40, most people who have migraines have had their first attack."</string>

    <string name="risk_section_3_heading">Gender</string>
    <string name="risk_section_3_body">"Women are three times more likely to have migraines. Headaches tend to affect boys more than girls during childhood, but by the time of puberty and beyond, more girls are affected."</string>

    <string name="risk_section_4_heading">Hormonal changes</string>
    <string name="risk_section_4_body">"If you're a woman who has migraines, you may find that your headaches begin just before or shortly after onset of menstruation."</string>


    <string name="complication_section_1_heading">Abdominal problems</string>
    <string name="complication_section_1_body">"Certain pain relievers called nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs), such as ibuprofen (Advil, Motrin IB, others), may cause abdominal pain, bleeding, ulcers and other complications, especially if taken in large doses or for a long period of time."</string>

    <string name="complication_section_2_heading">Medication-overuse headaches</string>
    <string name="complication_section_2_body">"If you take over-the-counter or prescription headache medications more than 10 days a month for three months, or in high doses, you may be setting yourself up for a serious complication known as medication-overuse headaches.

Medication-overuse headaches occur when medications not only stop relieving pain but also cause headaches. You then use more pain medication, which continues the cycle."</string>

    <string name="complication_section_3_heading">Serotonin syndrome</string>
    <string name="complication_section_3_body">"Serotonin syndrome is a rare, potentially life-threatening condition that occurs when your body has too much serotonin, which is a chemical found in your nervous system. It may occur if you take migraine medications called triptans and antidepressants known as selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs) or serotonin and norepinephrine reuptake inhibitors (SNRIs).

These medications naturally raise serotonin levels. When combined, they cause increased serotonin levels in your system, more than if you were taking one of these medications.

Triptans include medications such as sumatriptan (Imitrex) or zolmitriptan (Zomig). Some common SSRIs include sertraline (Zoloft), fluoxetine (Sarafem, Prozac) and paroxetine (Paxil). SNRIs include duloxetine (Cymbalta) and venlafaxine (Effexor XR)."</string>


    <string name="diagnosis_para_1">"If you have migraines or a family history of migraine headaches, your doctor trained in treating headaches (neurologist) will likely diagnose the condition on the basis of your medical history, a review of your symptoms, and a physical and neurological examination.

Your doctor may also recommend a variety of tests to rule out other possible causes for your pain if your condition is unusual, complex or suddenly becomes severe."</string>


    <string name="diagnosis_section_1_heading">Blood tests</string>
    <string name="diagnosis_section_1_body">"Your doctor may order blood tests to test for blood vessel problems, infections in your spinal cord or brain, and toxins in your system."</string>

    <string name="diagnosis_section_2_heading">Computerized tomography (CT) scan</string>
    <string name="diagnosis_section_2_body">"A CT scan uses a series of X-rays to create detailed cross-sectional images of your brain. This helps doctors diagnose tumors, infections, brain damage, bleeding in your brain and other possible medical problems that may be causing your headaches."</string>

    <string name="diagnosis_section_3_heading">Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)</string>
    <string name="diagnosis_section_3_body">"An MRI uses a powerful magnetic field and radio waves to produce detailed images of your brain and blood vessels.

MRI scans help doctors diagnose tumors, strokes, bleeding in your brain, infections, and other brain and nervous system (neurological) conditions."</string>

    <string name="diagnosis_section_4_heading">Spinal tap (lumbar puncture)</string>
    <string name="diagnosis_section_4_body">"If your doctor suspects an underlying condition, such as infections or bleeding in your brain, he or she may recommend a spinal tap (lumbar puncture).

In this procedure, a thin needle is inserted between two vertebrae in your lower back to extract a sample of cerebrospinal fluid for laboratory analysis."</string>


    <string name="treatment_heading_1">Pain-relieving medications</string>
    <string name="treatment_heading_2">Preventive medications</string>

    <string name="treatment_heading_1_section_1_heading">Pain relievers</string>
    <string name="treatment_heading_1_section_1_body">"Aspirin, or nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) such as ibuprofen (Advil, Motrin IB, others), may help relieve mild migraines.

Pain relievers, such as acetaminophen (Tylenol, others), also may help relieve mild migraines in some people.

Drugs marketed specifically for migraines, such as the combination of acetaminophen, aspirin and caffeine (Excedrin Migraine), also may ease moderate migraine pain, but aren't effective alone for severe migraines.

If taken too often or for long periods of time, these medications can lead to ulcers, gastrointestinal bleeding and medication-overuse headaches.

The prescription pain reliever indomethacin may help thwart a migraine headache and is available in suppository form, which may be helpful if you're nauseated."</string>

    <string name="treatment_heading_1_section_2_heading">Triptans</string>
    <string name="treatment_heading_1_section_2_body">"Many people with migraine attacks use triptans to treat their migraines. Triptans work by promoting constriction of blood vessels and blocking pain pathways in the brain.

Triptans effectively relieve the pain and other symptoms that are associated with migraines.

Medications include sumatriptan (Imitrex), rizatriptan (Maxalt), almotriptan (Axert), naratriptan (Amerge), zolmitriptan (Zomig), frovatriptan (Frova) and eletriptan (Relpax). Some triptans are available as nasal sprays and injections, in addition to tablets.

Side effects of triptans include nausea, dizziness, drowsiness and muscle weakness. They aren't recommended for people at risk of strokes and heart attacks.

A single-tablet combination of sumatriptan and naproxen sodium (Treximet) has proved to be more effective in relieving migraine symptoms than either medication on its own."</string>

    <string name="treatment_heading_1_section_3_heading">Ergots</string>
    <string name="treatment_heading_1_section_3_body">"Ergotamine and caffeine combination drugs (Migergot, Cafergot) are less effective than triptans. Ergots seem most effective in those whose pain lasts for more than 48 hours.

Ergotamine may cause worsened nausea and vomiting related to your migraines and other side effects, and it may also lead to medication-overuse headaches.

Dihydroergotamine (D.H.E. 45, Migranal) is an ergot derivative that is more effective and has fewer side effects than ergotamine. It's available as a nasal spray and in injection form. This medication may cause fewer side effects than ergotamine and is less likely to lead to medication-overuse headaches."</string>

    <string name="treatment_heading_1_section_4_heading">Anti-nausea medications</string>
    <string name="treatment_heading_1_section_4_body">"Because migraines are often accompanied by nausea, with or without vomiting, medication for nausea is appropriate and is usually combined with other medications. Frequently prescribed medications are chlorpromazine, metoclopramide (Reglan) or prochlorperazine (Compro)."</string>

    <string name="treatment_heading_1_section_5_heading">Opioid medications</string>
    <string name="treatment_heading_1_section_5_body">"Opioid medications containing narcotics, particularly codeine, are sometimes used to treat migraine headache pain for people who can't take triptans or ergot. Narcotics are habit-forming and are usually used only as a last resort."</string>

    <string name="treatment_heading_1_section_6_heading">Glucocorticoids (prednisone, dexamethasone)</string>
    <string name="treatment_heading_1_section_6_body">"A glucocorticoid may be used in conjunction with other medications to improve pain relief. Because of the risk of steroid toxicity, glucocorticoids shouldn't be used frequently."</string>


    <string name="treatment_heading_2_section_1_heading">Cardiovascular drugs</string>
    <string name="treatment_heading_2_section_1_body">"Beta blockers, which are commonly used to treat high blood pressure and coronary artery disease, may reduce the frequency and severity of migraines.

The beta blockers propranolol (Inderal La, Innopran XL, others), metoprolol tartrate (Lopressor) and timolol (Betimol) have proved effective for preventing migraines. Other beta blockers are also sometimes used for treatment of migraine. You may not notice improvement in symptoms for several weeks after taking these medications.

If you're older than age 60, use tobacco, or have certain heart or blood vessel conditions, doctors may recommend you take alternate medications instead of beta blockers.

Another class of cardiovascular medications (calcium channel blockers) used to treat high blood pressure and keep blood vessels from becoming narrow or wide, also may be helpful in preventing migraines and relieving symptoms from migraines. Verapamil (Calan, Verelan, others) is a calcium channel blocker that may help you.

In addition, the angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitor lisinopril (Zestril) may be useful in reducing the length and severity of migraines.

Researchers don't understand exactly why these cardiovascular medications prevent migraine attacks."</string>

    <string name="treatment_heading_2_section_2_heading">Antidepressants</string>
    <string name="treatment_heading_2_section_2_body">"Certain antidepressants help to prevent some types of headaches, including migraines. Tricyclic antidepressants may be effective in preventing migraines. You don't have to have depression to benefit from these drugs.

Tricyclic antidepressants may reduce the frequency of migraine headaches by affecting the level of serotonin and other brain chemicals. Amitriptyline is the only tricyclic antidepressant proved to effectively prevent migraine headaches. Other tricyclic antidepressants are sometimes used because they may have fewer side effects than amitriptyline.

These medications can cause dryness of mouth, constipation, weight gain and other side effects.

Another class of antidepressants called selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors hasn't been proved to be effective for migraine headache prevention.

However, research suggests that one serotonin and norepinephrine reuptake inhibitor, venlafaxine (Effexor XR), may be helpful in preventing migraines."</string>

    <string name="treatment_heading_2_section_3_heading">Anti-seizure drugs</string>
    <string name="treatment_heading_2_section_3_body">"Some anti-seizure drugs, such as valproate sodium (Depacon) and topiramate (Topamax), seem to reduce the frequency of migraine headaches.

In high doses, however, these anti-seizure drugs may cause side effects. Valproate sodium may cause nausea, tremor, weight gain, hair loss and dizziness. Valproate products should not be used in pregnant women for prevention of migraine headaches. Topiramate may cause diarrhea, nausea, weight loss, memory difficulties and concentration problems."</string>

    <string name="treatment_heading_2_section_4_heading">OnabotulinumtoxinA (Botox)</string>
    <string name="treatment_heading_2_section_4_body">"OnabotulinumtoxinA (Botox) has been shown to be helpful in treating chronic migraine headaches in adults.

During this procedure, injections are made in muscles of the forehead and neck. When this is effective, the treatment usually needs to be repeated every 12 weeks."</string>

    <string name="treatment_heading_2_section_5_heading">Pain relievers</string>
    <string name="treatment_heading_2_section_5_body">"Taking nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs, especially naproxen (Naprosyn), may help prevent migraines and reduce symptoms."</string>


    <string name="remedy_section_1_heading">Try muscle relaxation exercises</string>
    <string name="remedy_section_1_body">"Relaxation may help ease the pain of a migraine headache.

Relaxation techniques may include progressive muscle relaxation, meditation or yoga."</string>

    <string name="remedy_section_2_heading">Get enough sleep, but don\'t oversleep</string>
    <string name="remedy_section_2_body">"Get an adequate amount of sleep each night. It's best to go to bed and wake up at regular times, as well."</string>

    <string name="remedy_section_3_heading">Rest and relax</string>
    <string name="remedy_section_3_body">" If possible, rest in a dark, quiet room when you feel a headache coming on. Place an ice pack wrapped in a cloth on the back of your neck and apply gentle pressure to painful areas on your scalp."</string>

    <string name="remedy_section_4_heading">Keep a headache diary :-)</string>
    <string name="remedy_section_4_body">"Continue keeping your headache diary even after you see your doctor. It will help you learn more about what triggers your migraines and what treatment is most effective."</string>

    <string name="alternatives_para_1">"Ask your doctor if these treatments are right for you. Don't use feverfew, riboflavin or butterbur if you're pregnant or without first talking with your doctor."</string>

    <string name="alternative_section_1_heading">Acupuncture</string>
    <string name="alternative_section_1_body">"In this treatment, a practitioner inserts many thin, disposable needles into several areas of your skin at defined points. Clinical trials have found that acupuncture may be helpful for headache pain."</string>

    <string name="alternative_section_2_heading">Biofeedback</string>
    <string name="alternative_section_2_body">"Biofeedback appears to be effective in relieving migraine pain. This relaxation technique uses special equipment to teach you how to monitor and control certain physical responses related to stress, such as muscle tension."</string>

    <string name="alternative_section_3_heading">Massage therapy</string>
    <string name="alternative_section_3_body">"Massage therapy may help reduce the frequency of migraines. Researchers continue to study the effectiveness of massage therapy in preventing migraines."</string>

    <string name="alternative_section_4_heading">Cognitive behavioral therapy</string>
    <string name="alternative_section_4_body">"Cognitive behavioral therapy may benefit some people with migraines."</string>

    <string name="alternative_section_5_heading">Herbs, vitamins and minerals</string>
    <string name="alternative_section_5_body">"There is some evidence that the herb butterbur may prevent migraines or reduce their severity."</string>

    <string name="prevention_para_1">Whether or not you take preventive medications, you may benefit from lifestyle changes that can help reduce the number and severity of migraines.</string>

    <string name="prevention_section_1_heading">Avoid triggers</string>
    <string name="prevention_section_1_body">"If certain foods or odors seem to have triggered your migraines in the past, avoid them.

Your doctor may recommend you reduce your caffeine and alcohol intake and avoid tobacco.

In general, establish a daily routine with regular sleep patterns and regular meals. In addition, try to control stress."</string>

    <string name="prevention_section_2_heading">Exercise regularly</string>
    <string name="prevention_section_2_body">"Regular aerobic exercise reduces tension and can help prevent migraines. If your doctor agrees, choose any aerobic exercise you enjoy, including walking, swimming and cycling. Warm up slowly, however, because sudden, intense exercise can cause headaches.

Obesity is also thought to be a factor in migraine headaches, and regular exercise can help you maintain a healthy weight or lose weight."</string>

    <string name="prevention_section_3_heading">Reduce the effects of estrogen</string>
    <string name="prevention_section_3_body">"If you're a woman who has migraines and estrogen seems to trigger or make your headaches worse, you may want to avoid or reduce the medications you take that contain estrogen.

These medications include birth control pills and hormone replacement therapy. Talk with your doctor about the appropriate alternatives or dosages for you."</string>

</resources>
